Yamin Siahmargooei - Software Engineer

• Location: Gorgan, Iran

• Site: https://yamins.ir

 \bullet Email: yamin[dot]siahmargooei[at]gmail[dot]com

• Phone: +98-933-888-0330

• Telegram: https://t.me/yamins

• LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/yaminsm

• Github: https://github.com/yamin8000

• Stackoverflow: Profile Link

Summary

I'm a **Computer Engineer** specializing in **Software Engineering**. Skilled in **Android App Development** and have professional experience in **Kotlin** and **Java**. I also have semi-professional knowledge of **C**, **C++**, **C#**, **Python**, and **PHP** programming languages. As a Software Engineer, I'm interested in any type of software development; From **Embedded** programming utilizing AVR/ATmega with C, IoT projects by making use of Raspberry Pi/Arduino, **Back-End** projects using Ktor framework, **Full-stack** projects using Laravel, and mostly **Android** projects which are my main area of expertise.

Experiences

• Freelance Software Engineer Self-Employed Sep 2020 - Present

Most of my freelance work is associated with developing Android applications using Kotlin/Java (Compose/Views) and publishing them in App stores such as F-Droid and CafeBazaar. I also published some Android libraries in Maven Repository.

- Software Engineer Aryan Spad Sep 2020 November 2023 3 yrs and 3 mos I developed some Android applications for contractors and helped in the development of an Email Queue program using Kotlin and Ktor framework. I was also part of a small team that helped to develop multiple websites using Laravel, .NET Core and WordPress
- Gap year Career Break
 Dec 2018 Sep 2020
 Mandatory Military Service

• IoT Apprentice Golestan University

Dec 2017 - Aug 2018 9 mos

I worked on a project developing a platform for devices in

IoT using a Raspberry Pi as a Gateway

Technical Support Specialist Xperian.ir
 Jan 2014 - Feb 2017
 3 yrs 2 mos
 Technical Support for WordPress and content creation about Sony Xperia devices

Education

• Golestan University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Engineering Sep 2014 - Sep 2018

Software Engineering

Thesis: Implementation of the server and gateway application based on the client-server model in the framework of an Internet of Things network

Skills

• Programming Languages

- Professional: Kotlin, Java

- Intermediate: SQL, C#

- **Basic:** PHP, Python, C, C++

• Tools and Technologies

- IDEs: Android Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio

- **DBMs:** SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL

- GitHub, Gitlab

- Material Design

- Laravel

- Industry Knowledge
 - Android Development
 - Object-Oriented Programming
 - Git
 - Data Structures
 - Refactoring
 - Clean Code
 - Clean Architecture
 - Regular Expressions

Languages

Projects

Android

• PrettyPersianNumbers

I created an Android library to convert a number to a word for Persian/Farsi using Kotlin/JVM and published it to maven repository.

• Dooz

A simple pen-and-paper game. I created this implementation using Kotlin and Jetpack Compose for Android devices.

• freeDictionaryApp A simple android application for freeDictionaryAPI, published in F-Droid and CafeBazaar.

• Gauge

A fusion of classic and modern Gauges with some customization options for Jetpack Compose.

Web

• Androlaw

I was part of a three-man group that designed and implemented this website. I helped in design and implementation of various pages on this website using Laravel, Blade, Bootstrap, and Javascript. My work included but not limited to implementing various controllers/services using PHP, designing frontend pages using Blade/HTML/CSS/JavaScript and bootstrap.

• ansp.ir

I helped in the design and development of the site

back-end and databases, using . NET Core and PostgreSQL.

IoT

• Monex

I designed and implemented an Android App used as the interface of the Monex device. The app is implemented using Kotlin and Jetpack Compose UI and communicates with an Arduino device with USB Serial.

JVM(Java, Kotlin)

• coinex4i

CoinEx Exchange API JVM Library created with help of the Retrofit library.

• grand-node-java-client

A JVM client for GrandNode2 API powered by Retrofit and Project Lombok.

• SpaceTradersKMP

SpaceTraders API wrapper for Kotlin Multiplatform (https://spacetraders.io/).

• InstaCLI

A CLI client for Instagram created using Retrofit, instagram4j, jackson and Kotlin Coroutines.

TwitterScrapper

A simple CLI tool for scrapping Tweets from Nitter without authentication

Other projects

• Github: https://github.com/yamin8000